你们知道这是最后一次
Do you realize this is the last time
我们以六个单身朋友的身份
we'll be here in the coffeehouse
在咖啡厅共聚一堂吗
as six single people?
咖啡厅要怎么了
What's happening to the coffeehouse?
从现在开始  是你们四个好朋友
Yeah, from now on, it's gonna be the four of you guys
我跟我太太了
and me and the missus.
我的小女人  好妻子  老老婆
The little woman. The wife. The old ball and chain.
-老  -你是年轻性感的老婆
- Old? - The young, hot ball and chain.
-好多了  -我们得走了
- Much better. - We gotta go.
去哪里
Where?
我要去拿婚纱
We're gonna pick up the wedding dress
然后跟妈一起吃午餐
then we're gonna have lunch with mom.
乔伊  你也要去和我妈吃饭吗
Joey you're having lunch with my mom?
不  我只听到了"午餐"
No, I just heard lunch.
不过我当然愿意去啊
But yeah, I can go. Sure!
正好他们都走了
Actually, I'm glad they're leaving.
有件事我得跟你谈一谈
'Cause I need to talk to you about something.
-什么事  -这话说来有点尴尬
- What's up? - This may be a little awkward.
如果你想借钱  有点不是时候
Listen, if you want to borrow money, its kind of a bad time.
明天晚上我得请128个人吃晚餐
I'm buying dinner for 128 people tomorrow night.
不是借钱
No, it's not that.
我现在不是以你朋友的身分跟你说话...
Now what I'm going to say to you, I'm not saying as your friend.
我要以莫妮卡大哥的身份跟你谈
I'm saying as it as Monica's older brother.
但你还是我朋友吧
But you're still my friend?
接下来的几分钟不是
Not for the next few minutes.
现在你还是我的伴郎吗
During this time, are you still my best man?
不是
No.
我还可以叫你罗斯吗
Do I still call you Ross?
你们明天就要结婚了
You guys are getting married tomorrow,
我真的替你们俩高兴
and I couldn't be more thrilled for both of you.
但身为她的大哥  我得告诉你一件事
But as Monica's older brother, I have to tell you this:
如果你敢伤害我妹妹...
If you ever hurt my little sister...
如果你敢让她不快乐...
if you ever cause her any unappiness of any kind,
天涯海角我都会找到你...
...I will hunt you down...
然后痛扁你一顿
...and kick your ass.
怎么了  我是认真的
What? I'm serious.
兄弟  别闹了  我不是在开玩笑
Dude! Stop it! I'm not kidding here.
我听到你的话了...
I hear what you're saying...
谢谢你的警告
...and thanks for the warning.
别客气
No problem.
我们又是朋友了
Are we friends again?
-对  -好
- Yeah. - Okay.
你肯定不相信刚刚莫妮卡她哥跟我说了什么
You won't believe what Monica's older brother just said to me!
你在做什么  莫妮卡
What you doing, Mon?
我在罗列婚礼上
I'm making a list of all the things
可能会出差错的事情
that are most likely to go wrong at the wedding.
给自己打个预防针
So that way I can be prepared.
哪些事会出差错
What are they?
到目前为止有  婚纱忘了取
So far, I have my bride's maids dresses won't get picked up,
我的面纱不见了  或是我忘了拿蓝色的东西
...my veil gets lost or I don't have something blue.
那都是我负责的事
Those are all the things I’m responsible for!
我得做好万全准备
I had to go with the odds, Rach.
伙计们
Hey, guys.
你们还记得之前我去试镜
Remember that audition I had a while ago
没有拿到那个角色的事吗
and I didn't get the part?
-那个广告  -不是
- The commercial? - No.
-那部舞台剧  -不是
- That play? - No.
-另一部舞台剧  -不是
- That other play? - No.
-那部电影  -对了
- The movie? - Yes!
关于飞行员和他会开飞机的狗
The one with the pilot and his dog who flies planes?
不是  但那部真的很伤感
No. But, man, that one hurt.
这部电影描述的是
Yes, that's the one about the soldiers
-一战的士兵  -是啊
- who fight in World War I! - Oh, yeah.
当年我们称其为"大战"
Back then we called it "The Great War."
真的是大战
It really was.
他们录取的那个演员不演了
Anyway, the guy they wanted backed out!
我今天就要开始拍戏了
And now they want me. I start shooting today!
恭喜
Congratulations!
等等  今天有彩排晚宴
Wait, wait. I can't start today. Today's the rehearsal dinner.
我一定会赶过去的
I'll be done by then.
那么太棒了  你成电影明星了
Oh. Then way to go, you big movie star!
待会见  我要去跟纳粹作战了
I'll see you guys over there.. I'm off to fight the Nazis.
等一下  乔伊
Wait, Joey.
纳粹是我们二战的敌人  不是一战
We fought the Nazis in WWII, not WWI.
好吧
Okay.
我们一战的敌人是谁
Who was in WWI?
你说吧
Go ahead.
你要迟到了  快去...
You're gonna be late! Go! Go!
我们一战的敌人是谁
Who did we fight in WWI?
-墨西哥  -对  非常棒
- Mexico? - Yes. Very good.
-乔伊  我们准备好了  -我也是
- Hey, Joey. We're ready. - Yeah, me too.
理查  我们准备好了
Richard, we're ready for you.
乔伊·崔比安尼
Joey Tribbiani,
这位是理查·克洛斯比  他要饰演文森
this is Richard Crosby. He's playing Vincent.
我要跟你演对手戏
I'm doing my scenes with you?
很高兴能认识你  乔伊
Nice to meet you, Joey.
我不敢相信  这太不可思议了
I can't believe this. This is incredible.
你刚刚拿下奥斯卡金像奖
You just won an Oscar.
我没有
No, I didn't.
我知道你拿了
I think you did.
我三次都落选了
I think I lost, three times.
-饼干  你要...  -不
- Cookie? Would you...? - No.
再过一小时我们就要正式开拍了
Okay, we're about an hour away from getting the scene lit.
你们不介意的话
So, if you guys don't mind,
-能对几遍戏吗  -没问题
- can we run it a couple of times? - Yeah, sure.
好了  我们开始吧
All right. Let's do it.
好了  开拍
And... Action!
我们得找到其他士兵
We have to find the rest of the platoon!
算了吧  他们已经不在了
Forget the platoon, the platoon is gone!
什么
What?
他们都死了  面对现实吧  东尼
The platoon's dead! Face facts, Tony!
我们该怎么办  我们没有援兵  没有食物
So what are we gonna do? We have no reinforcements. No food.
地下室还有食物储备
No, we still have food in the basement!
有马铃薯和干意大利面
I saw potatoes and some dry pasta!
等一下  乔伊  你一直在摸脸
Hang on a minute. Joey, you keep touching your face.
有什么问题吗
Is something wrong?
不  没有
No. No.
我觉得可以把这作为角色的标志性动作
I thought it might be a cool character thing.
他是个喜欢摸脸的人
He's a face toucher.
还是算了吧
I don't think so.
我们从理查最后一句台词开始  开拍
Let's take it back to Richard's last lines. Action!
虽然我们没有武器  但我们还有食物
We may not have any weapons, but we still have food.
我在地下室看到马铃薯和干意大利面
in the basement I saw potatoes and some dry pasta,
跟几罐金枪鱼
...and a few tins of tuna!
亲爱的  我们得走了
Honey, we gotta go!
这个问题真的很难启齿
Here's a question you never want to ask:
我爸打电话来问
My dad just called and wanted to know
能借用你的珍珠项链吗
if he could borrow one of your pearl necklaces.
他有提到他的领口剪栽是哪种吗
Did he say what kind of neckline he's wearing?
没有
No.
我只见过他一次  但我猜...
I just met him once, but I'm guessing...
是低胸的
...plunging?
他是那种不显摆不罢休的老爸
He is more of a if-you've-got-it-flaunt-it kind of father.
我没有那种项链  我去问问瑞秋有没有适合的
I don't have anything like that, but let me go see if Rachel does.
对  把更多的人扯进来吧
Yes, include more people in this.
你知道明天这个时候
Do you realize that at this time tomorrow
我们就要结婚了吗
we're gonna be getting married?
我明天晚上有约了
I have a date tomorrow night.
我不敢相信我们真的办到了
I can't believe we made it.
别一副很讶异的样子
Don't sound so surprised.
对不起  但是...
I'm sorry, but...
-没事  -怎么了
- Nothing. - What?
说实话  自从我们订婚以后
Well, honestly? Ever since we got engaged...
我一直在等什么事情发生逼你退缩
...I've been waiting for something to flip you out.
真的吗  我也是
Honestly? Me too.
-真的吗  -对
- Really? - Yeah.
我一直觉得会有蠢事发生
I keep thinking that something stupid is gonna come up
然后我会做...
and I'll go all...
钱德勒会做的事
Well, Chandler.
-但什么事都没发生  -我很高兴
- But nothing has. - I'm so glad.
谢谢你在这段时间一直都非常冷静
Thank you for staying so calm during this.
这也让我能保持冷静
It's made me stay calm.
我可能会比现在还不淡定
I could've been worse.
我马上回来
I'll be right there.
如果你在星期六前打电话来
If you're calling before Saturday,
这里是莫妮卡跟钱德勒家
you've reached Monica and Chandler.
但如果你在星期六后打电话来
But if you're calling after Saturday,
这里是宾氏夫妇家
you've reached Mr. And Mrs. Bing.
请留言给...宾氏夫妇
Please leave a message for... the Bings!
嘿  墨琳
Hey, Maureen! Hi!
钱德勒  她是我表妹墨琳
Gosh, Chandler, this is my cousin, Maureen.
我们是宾氏夫妇
We're the Bings.
嗨  你们打扮得都很漂亮
Hi! You guys look so beautiful.
宾先生跟宾太太
Mr. And Mrs. Bing!
莫妮卡
Monica.
跟你说  我以"大哥的身分"跟钱德勒谈过
Just so you know, I had my "older brother" talk with Chandler.
你说了什么
What is that?
我告诉他如果他敢伤害你...
I told him that if he ever hurt you...
天涯海角我都会找到他  然后痛扁他一顿
...I would hunt him down and kick his ass.
大家这都是怎么了  我是认真的
What is the matter with everybody? I'm serious.
我真的会痛扁他一顿
I would kick his ass!
罗斯  拜托  我的妆要花了
Ross, please, my makeup!
-钱德勒  -妈
- Chandler. - Mom.
谢谢你记得穿...衣服来
Thanks for wearing... something.
我真的很兴奋
Honey, this is so exciting!
我以为我们害得你不敢结婚了呢
I thought we screwed you up so bad this day would never come.
你想想  很快地就会添出不少宾氏小宝宝
Just think, soon there will be lots of little Bings.
我不敢相信我就要回去工作了
I can't believe I have to go back to work after this
让人家喷一脸口水
and get spit on again.
你算幸运的  至少喷你口水的人很有名
You're lucky. At least the people that spit on you are famous.
谁对你喷过口水
Who spits on you?
我不想谈工作的事
I don't want to talk about work.
宾太太  这是我爸妈朱迪跟杰克·盖勒
Mrs. Bing? These are my parents, Judy and Jack Geller.
很高兴能见到你
It's lovely to meet you.
你是他妈还是他爸
Are you his mother or father?
杰克
Jack!
怎么了  我没见过变性人
What? I've never seen one before.
爸  罗斯在那边去  跟他谈一谈吧
Dad, there's Ross. Why don't you go talk to him.
我甚至没机会假装我不在意
I didn't even have a chance to act as though I'm okay with it!
大家好
Hello, all.
嗨...爸
Hi... Dad.
嗨  宾先生
Hi, Mr. Bing.
-诺拉  -查尔斯
- Nora. - Charles.
-很高兴你们两个都来了  -对
- It's so great to see you both here. - Yes.
虽然某些人衣不遮体
Although we may be seeing too much of some people.
你不觉得自己太老了  不该穿那种衣服吗
Aren't you a little old to wear a dress like that?
你不觉得自己多了根把儿
Don't you have a little too much penis
不该穿那种衣服吗
to wear a dress like that?
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
你当然可以痛扁他  儿子
Of course you can kick his ass, son.
你想痛扁任何人都没有问题
You could kick anyone's ass you want to.
谢谢你们
Thanks, you guys.
-瑞秋  -怎么了
- Rach, Rach? - Yeah?
快去跟钱德勒他爸聊天
Could you do me a favor to talk to Chandler's dad
别让他钱德勒的妈妈杠上
and try to keep him away from Chandler's mom.
但我不知道他长什么样子
But I don't know what he looks like.
他穿着黑色连衣裙
He's the man in the black dress.
嗨  我是瑞秋  莫妮卡跟钱德勒的朋友
Hi! I'm Rachel, a friend of Monica and Chandler's.
-我是阿曼达  -我懂了
- I'm Amanda. - Oh, I get it.
"是男人  才怪"
"A man, duh!"
请大家听我说
Could I have everyone's attention, please?
-我是罗斯·盖勒  -罗斯·盖勒博士
- I'm Ross Geller. - Dr. Ross Geller.
爸  拜托  我刚刚说过...
Dad, please. As I was saying...
我是罗斯·盖勒博士
...I'm Dr. Ross Geller.
我是伴郎
And I'm the best man.
这段婚姻对我来说有双重意义...
This marriage is doubly special for me...
不只因为新郎是我的好朋友...
...because not only is the groom my best friend...
更因为新娘是我的妹妹
...but the bride is my little sister.
她是所有男人梦寐以求的好妹妹
She's the greatest sister a guy could ask for.
请大家跟我一起举杯...
So if you'd all please join me in raising a glass
敬这对新人
to the couple we're here to celebrate.
-敬宾氏夫妇  -敬宾氏夫妇
- To the Bings. - To the Bings!
我要去熨婚纱了
I'm gonna steam my wedding dress.
谁负责保护它不出任何问题
Who wants the responsibility of making sure nothing happens to it?
-我来负责  -谁要负责  有人愿意吗
- I'll do it. - Who wants it? Anybody?
-我说了我来负责  -没有人吗
- I said, I'll do it. - Nobody wants to do it?
好吧  那么我就自己来
All right, I'll do it myself.
我不会搞砸的
I'm not gonna screw it up.
你说得对  对不起  今晚你帮了大忙
You're right. I'm sorry. Actually you were a big help tonight.
谢谢你帮忙将我奶奶
Yeah, and thanks for putting my grandmother in the cab
安全地送回酒店
and making sure she got to the hotel safely.
当然  那就是我的职责
Of course! That's what I'm here for.
好吧  对不起
Okay. Sorry.
什么奶奶
What grandmother?
你跑到哪里去了
Where have you been?
我送我爸妈回酒店
Taking my parents back to the hotel.
-你要回去工作了  -对
- What? Are you going back to work? - Yeah.
-很酷的太阳眼镜  -谢谢夸奖
- Nice shades. - Thanks.
我想如果能戴上它拍戏
I figure if I wear these in my scenes,
我的眼睛就不会被喷到口水了
I won't get spit in my eyes.
如果我没有记错
And, if I remember correctly,
雷朋是一次大战的正式赞助商
Ray-Ban was the official sponsor of WWI.
太棒了  帅啊
Great! All right!
-待会见  -好吧
- I'll see you later. - All right.
钱德勒在哪里
Where's Chandler?
他大概在瑞秋的房间里
I think he's in Rachel's room. See ya.
钱德勒
Chandler?
莫妮卡在吗
Is Monica here?
她在熨婚纱  怎么了
She's steaming her dress. Why? What's up?
-我觉得钱德勒走了  -什么
- I think Chandler's gone. - What?
-他留下了这个  -告诉莫妮卡我很抱歉
- He left that. - "Tell Monica I'm sorry."
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
怎么了
What's up?
"告诉莫妮卡我很抱歉"
"Tell Monica I'm sorry."
你自己告诉她去
Tell her yourself.
我的天啊  钱德勒走了
Oh, my God. Chandler just left, though?
或许事情不是我们想的那样  或许他是说
Maybe it's not what we think. Maybe it's:
"告诉莫妮卡我很抱歉  我把牛奶都喝光了"
"Tell Monica I'm sorry I drank the last of the milk."
或许他写这张字条是想告诉她
Or maybe he was writing to tell her
他改了名字
that he's changed his name:
"告诉莫妮卡我叫抱歉"
"Tell Monica I'm Sorry."
这表示他临阵脱逃了
I think it means he freaked out and left!
别那么消极
Don't be so negative!
天啊  有没有可能"抱歉"
Good God, isn't it possible that "Sorry"
现在就坐在里面
is sitting in there right now?
菲比  我想罗斯说得对  我们该怎么办
Phoebe, I think Ross is right. What are we gonna do?
我得去找他  把他带回来
I'm gonna have to go find him and bring him back.
你们别让莫妮卡发现这件事  好吗
You make sure Monica does not find out, okay?
如果你没办法找到他  把他带回来...
But if you don't find him and bring him back...
天涯海角我都会找到你  然后痛扁你一顿
...I am gonna hunt you down and kick your ass!
乔伊  你能跟我对一下台词吗
Joey? Can you go through these lines with me?
天啊  他们才帮我补好妆
Oh, man, they just re-did my makeup.
-只对最后两页  -好吧
- Just the last two pages. - All right.
我发现那张照片了
I found the picture!
照片  什么照片
Picture? What picture?
我在你的背包里发现了我太太的照片
The picture of my wife I found in your pack.
你能把剧本放下来吗
Could you lower the script?
我不想
I don't want to.
我得看到你的脸  才能根据你的反应表演
I need to see your face so I can play off your reaction.
好吧  听我说
Okay, look.
我知道你的演技很棒
I know you're this great actor
演过很多莎翁名剧...
and play all those Shakespeare guys and stuff,
但你喷得我满脸是口水
but you're spitting all over me, man.
-那当然  -你知道自己会喷口水
- Of course I am! - You know you've been spitting on me?
真正的演员都会喷
That's what real actors do.
发音是好演员的标志
Enunciation is the mark of a good actor.
发音清晰时就会喷口水
And when you enunciate, you spit!
我不知道这件事
Didn't know that.
谢了  好吧  看我的
Thanks. Okay, check it out.
照片  什么照片
Picture? What picture?
甘瑟  你看到钱德勒了吗
Gunther, have you seen Chandler?
我没有看到他
No, I haven't seen him.
-该死  -他明天要结婚了  对吧
- Damn. - He's getting married tomorrow, right?
对  别担心  一切都会没事的
Yes. Don't worry. Everything's fine.
-明天婚礼上见  -我没有被邀请
- We'll see you tomorrow at the wedding. - I wasn't invited.
那么后天见
Then we'll see you the day after tomorrow.
妈  爸
Mom? Dad?
你在这里做什么
What are you guys doing here?
你们经常提起这个地方
You kids talk about this place so much,
我们想看看这里到底有什么特别
we thought we'd see what all the fuss is about.
我知道为什么女孩们喜欢来这里
I certainly see why the girls like coming here.
为什么
Why?
为了吧台后面那个性感金发大帅哥
The sexy blond behind the counter.
-甘瑟  -她刚刚把他列入了她的名单
- Gunther? - Your mother just added him to her list.
什么  你的名单
What? Your list?
我们允许对方与之上床的异性名单
Yeah, the list that of people we're allowed to sleep.
我知道是什么的名单
No, no. I know what the list is.
快坐下吧  喝杯咖啡
Come on, sit down. Have a cup of joe.
爸  我没空  抱歉
Dad, I can't. I'm sorry.
如果你看到钱德勒  告诉他我在找他
If you see Chandler, could you just tell him I'm looking for him?
如果你看到丽塔·莫雷诺  告诉她我在找她
And if you see Rita Moreno, let her know I'm looking for her.
开拍
Action!
我发现那张照片了
I found the picture!
什么照片
What picture?
我在你的背包里发现了我太太的照片
The picture of my wife, in your pack!
你偷翻我的私人物品
You went through my personal property?
你的背包里为什么会有宝丽蒂的照片
Why do you have a picture of Paulette in your pack?
文森  因为我们...
Because, Vincent, we were lovers...
交往过两年
...for two years!
卡  太棒了
Cut! Wonderful!
真的是太棒了
Great scene!
你真的很棒
You were awesome.
最后那一段  你喷得我的脸都湿了
In that last speech, you soaked me.
这是明天的通告表
Here's your call sheet for tomorrow.
明天我不工作
I'm not working tomorrow.
-现在得工作了  -不  你得帮我这个忙
- You are now. -  No! No! I can't! You gotta get me out of it!
我已经有约了  这件事非常重要
I've got plans! Important plans!
-罗斯说还是没有钱德勒的消息  -天啊
- Ross said still no word from Chandler. - Oh, man.
但他们发现了他奶奶
But he did say that they found the grandmother
在第五大道上游荡
wandering down 5th Avenue.
好吧  至少找到一个人了
Okay, well, there's one down.
今天我就要结婚了
I'm getting married today!
我断了一根肋骨  但我不在乎
I think I just cracked a rib, but I don't care.
今天我要结婚了
Because today's my wedding day!
我终于要结婚了
My day is finally here!
或许她不会注意到他不见了
She might not even notice he's gone.
我要开始准备了
I'm gonna start getting ready!
我们不能让她开始准备  这太可怕了
We can't let her start getting ready. This is too awful!
但等她换上婚纱  而他又没有出现
But she'll be in the gown and then he won't show up...
这时候她就得脱掉婚纱...
...then she'll have to take off the gown...
冷静点  你不能在这里抓狂
Stop it, stop it, Rachel. You can't do this here.
对不起  抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
真是太伤感了
It's just so sad.
振作一点  别让她看到你这个样子
You got to pull yourself together. Monica can't see you like this.
她会发现不对劲的
Then she'll know something's wrong.
我知道  天啊
I know. I know. Oh, God!
没有面纸了
There's no tissue.
你能拿张卫生纸给我吗
Can you grab me some toilet paper?
卫生纸也没有了
Oh, that's gone too.
这里是莫妮卡的卫生间吧
This is Monica's bathroom, right?
-我找到了一张  -好吧
- I found one. - Okay.
-拿去吧  -谢谢
- Here you go. - Thank you.
天啊
Oh, God.
能再给我一张吗
Can I have another one?
没问题
Sure.
你需要牙线吗
Do you need some floss?
我无法想像如果他不出现
I just can't imagine what is gonna happen
会发生什么事
if Chandler doesn't show up.
这里有一大堆卫生纸
Here's a whole bunch.
她会在礼堂等他...
She'll be at the wedding waiting for him
大家会低声说"那个可怜的姑娘"
and people will be whispering, "Oh, that poor girl."
然后她得回来这里独自一个人生活
Then she'll have to come back here and live alone.
-我的天啊  -怎么了
- Oh, my God. - What?
垃圾桶有一根验孕棒
There was a pregnancy test in the garbage.
是阳性反应
And it's positive.
莫妮卡怀孕了
Monica's pregnant.
我猜她不会寂寞了
So I guess she won't be totally alone.